Lillian Sweet Allen Papers
Lillian Sweet Allen Papers
1905-1961
Allen, Lillian Sweet.
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American genealogist. Correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, and some published material relating to the genealogy of the Bly, Rich, Sweet, Towner, Vaughn and Whitford families.
148806
Biographical History
Lillian Sweet Allen was an American genealogist. Families of interest to her include the Bly, Rich, Sweet, Towner, Vaughn and Whitford families.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lillian Sweet Allen Papers are divided into correspondence, subject files, manuscripts and published material. Correspondence (1905-1961) includes letters written by and to Mrs. Allen and Jared E. Allen. They relate to genealogical matters and are arranged alphabetically by subject (i.e. family name). Within each family the correspondence is filed chronologically. One Subject file contains undated photographs of various members of the Sweet family. Manuscripts contains notes and notebooks of Mrs. Sweet concerning the various families. These materials are arranged alphabetically by type and then alphabetically by family name. Finally, Published materials contains a book and two newspaper clippings, arranged alphabetically by type.
Arrangement of the Collection
See Scope and Contents above.
Subject and Genre Headings
Allen, Lillian Sweet Archives.; Bly family Genealogy.; Rich family Genealogy.; Sweet family Genealogy.; Towner family Genealogy.; Whitford family Genealogy.; Women genealogists, United States.; Correspondence.; Genealogies (histories); Notebooks.; Photographs.; Genealogists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1963.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Bly family, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
  - Rich family, 1924-1926 (Box 1)
  - Sweet family, 1905; 1913,; 1922-1927,; 1947,; 1961,; undated (Box 1)
  - Towner family, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Vaughn family, 1925-1926 (Box 1)
  - Whitford family, 1924-1926 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Photographs (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Notes
    - Bly family (Box 1)
    - Rich family, with galley proof (Box 1)
    - Sweet family, and published material (Box 1)
    - Vaughn family (Box 1)
    - Whitford family (Box 1)
  - Notebooks (Box 1)
  - Notebooks (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Book, Ancestral Tablets, by William Whitmore (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1)